{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A district road with a bituminous pavement has a horizontal curve of 1000 m for a design speed of 75 km ph. The super-elevation is", "opta": "1 in 40", "optb": "1 in 50", "optc": "1 in 60", "optd": "1 in 70", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum value of camber provided for thin bituminous surface hill roads, is", "opta": "2.2%", "optb": "2.5%", "optc": "3.0%", "optd": "3.5%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Design of horizontal and vertical alignments, super-elevation, sight distance and grades, is worst affected by", "opta": "width of the vehicle", "optb": "length of the vehicle", "optc": "height of the vehicle", "optd": "speed of the vehicle", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thickness of a pavement may be reduced considerably by", "opta": "compaction of soil", "optb": "stabilisation of soil", "optc": "drainage of soil", "optd": "combination of all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total length of a valley formed by two gradients - 3% and + 2% curve between the two tangent points to provide a rate of change of centrifugal acceleration 0.6 m/sec2, for a design speed 100 km ph, is", "opta": "16.0 m", "optb": "42.3 m", "optc": "84.6 m", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Traffic engineering only includes", "opta": "planning of regulatory measures", "optb": "design and application of control devices", "optc": "analysis of traffic characteristics", "optd": "traffic opeation", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the movement of vehicles at an intersection of two roads, without any interference, the type of grade separator generally preferred to, is", "opta": "delta", "optb": "trumpet", "optc": "diamond interchange", "optd": "clover leaf.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the ruling gradient on any highway is 3%, the gradient provided on the curve of 300 metre radius, is", "opta": "2.00%", "optb": "2.25%", "optc": "2.50%", "optd": "2.75%", "opte": "3.00%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "As per recommendations of I.R.C., traffic volume study is carried out for rural roads for 7 days continuously during", "opta": "harvesing", "optb": "lean season", "optc": "harvesting and lean season", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The minimum ratio of the radii of two circular curves of a compound curve, is kept", "opta": "1.25", "optb": "1.5", "optc": "1.75", "optd": "2.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Border Roads Organisation for hilly regions, was formed in", "opta": "1947", "optb": "1954", "optc": "1958", "optd": "1960", "opte": "1962", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The Border Roads Organization (BRO) was conceived and raised in the year 1960 by Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru, the great visionary and the first Prime Ministry of India. This was done with the aim of coordinating the speedy development of network of roads in the North and the North Eastern border regions of the country. BRO is regarded as a symbol of nation-building, national integration and an inseparable component in maintaining the security and integrity of the country."}, {"question": "Pick up the incorrect statement from the following. The super-elevation on roads is", "opta": "directly proportional to width of pavement", "optb": "directly proportional to velocity of vehicles", "optc": "inversely proportional to acceleration due to gravity", "optd": "inversely proportional to the radius of curvature.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The weaving length of a roadway is the distance", "opta": "between the channelising islands", "optb": "equal to half circumference", "optc": "equal to total width of adjoining radial roads", "optd": "equal to diameter of rotary.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Road makers along roads from the edge of a kerb should not be less than", "opta": "40 cm", "optb": "45 cm", "optc": "50 cm", "optd": "55 cm", "opte": "60 cm", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Traffic surveys are carried out", "opta": "to know the type of traffic", "optb": "to determine the facilities to traffic regulations", "optc": "to design proper drainage system", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The formula for calculating the depth of concrete pavements suggested by Goldbeck, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If A is the projected area of a vehicle in square metres, V is speed of the vehicles in kilometres per hour and C is a constant, then the wind resistance R to the moving vehicles, is given by", "opta": "R = CAV", "optb": "R = CAV2", "optc": "R = CAV3", "optd": "", "opte": "R = C2AV", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The usual width of parapet walls along Highways in hilly region, is", "opta": "50 cm", "optb": "60 cm", "optc": "70 cm", "optd": "80 cm", "opte": "100 cm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The road foundation for modern highways construction, was developed by", "opta": "Tresguet", "optb": "Telford", "optc": "Macadam", "optd": "Tresguet and Telford simultaneously", "opte": "Telford and Macadam simultaneously.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If N is deviation angle the length L of a parabolic vetical curve for overtaking sight distance S, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "opte": "Both (A) and (C)", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If C is basic capacity per lane, V is velocity in km/hour, S is stopping distance pluslength of the vehicles in metres, the formula  is applicable to", "opta": "district roads", "optb": "two lane roads", "optc": "two lane roads in one direction", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Width of vehicles affects the width of", "opta": "lanes", "optb": "shoulders", "optc": "parking spaces", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "First operation during the detailed survey of a hill road, is", "opta": "hydrological and soil surveys", "optb": "adjustment of alignment along with curves", "optc": "derivation of longitudinal and cross-sections", "optd": "fixation of Bench Marks", "opte": "staking the ground.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The period of long term plan for the development of roads in India, known as Bombay Plan (Aug. 1958), is", "opta": "5 years", "optb": "10 years", "optc": "15 years", "optd": "20 years", "opte": "25 years", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In water bound macadam roads, binding material, is", "opta": "sand", "optb": "stone dust", "optc": "cement", "optd": "brick dust.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to Highway Research Board of U.S.A. practical land width, is", "opta": "2.7 m", "optb": "3.0 m", "optc": "3.3 m", "optd": "3.6 m", "opte": "4.5 m", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Design of flexible pavements is based on", "opta": "mathematical analysis", "optb": "empirical formulae", "optc": "a compromise of pure theory and pure empirical formula", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The efficiency of the brakes of a vehicle depends upon", "opta": "condition of road surface", "optb": "condition of the tyres", "optc": "presence of the show moisture", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum super-elevation on hill roads should not exceed", "opta": "5%", "optb": "7%", "optc": "8%", "optd": "10%", "opte": "15%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The type of transition curves generally provided on hill roads, is", "opta": "circular", "optb": "cubic parabola", "optc": "Lemniscate", "optd": "spiral.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum safe speed on roads, depends on the", "opta": "type of the highway", "optb": "type of road surface", "optc": "type of curves", "optd": "sight distance", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The basic formula for determination of pavement thickness was first suggested by", "opta": "Spanglar", "optb": "Picket", "optc": "Kelly", "optd": "Goldbeck", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Increase in traffic volume, due to increase in transport vehicles, is known as", "opta": "development traffic", "optb": "normal traffic growth", "optc": "generated traffic growth", "optd": "current traffic", "opte": "none of these.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If R is the radius of a main curve and L is the length of the transition curve, the shift of the curve, is", "opta": "L/24 R", "optb": "L2/24 R", "optc": "L3/24 R", "optd": "L4/24 R", "opte": "L/12 R", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The weight of vehicles affects", "opta": "pavement thickness", "optb": "ruling gradient", "optc": "limiting gradient", "optd": "design of bridges", "opte": "all the above.", "ans": "E", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "During reconnaissance, the general route of the alignment is selected", "optb": "After reconnaissance, a trace is cut for the alignment", "optc": "Last stage is the detailed surveys for desired geometries'of the highway", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Deviation of the alignment of a trace cut may be permitted in areas involving", "opta": "land slides", "optb": "sand dunes", "optc": "dens", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If cross slope of a country is 10% to 25%, the terrain is classified as", "opta": "rolling", "optb": "mountainous", "optc": "steep", "optd": "plain.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Shoulders for high traffic volume roads, should", "opta": "be stable throughout the year to be used by vehicles in the case of emergency", "optb": "support and protect the ends of carriage ways", "optc": "not allow entrance of water to sub-grade", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "According to the recommendations of Nagpur Conference, the width formation of an ideal National Highway in hard rock cutting, is", "opta": "8.9 m", "optb": "7.9 m", "optc": "6.9 m", "optd": "6.5 m", "opte": "7.5 m", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The absolute minimum radius of horizontal curve for a design speed 60 km ph is", "opta": "131 m", "optb": "210 m", "optc": "360 m", "optd": "none of these.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Volume of traffic which would immediately use a new road or an improved one when opened to traffic, is known", "opta": "development traffic", "optb": "current traffic", "optc": "general traffic", "optd": "normal traffic growth.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Pick up the correct statement from the following:", "opta": "Safety fences are provided on either side of a roadway if embankments are in excess of 6 metres", "optb": "Safety fences are provided on outside of the curves of radii less than 750 m if the embankments are between 3 metres and 6 metres", "optc": "Guard stones are provided at 2.5 metres intervals if embankments are between 1.6 metres to 3 metres", "optd": "All the above.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In India the modes of transportation, in the order of their importance, are", "opta": "air transport, shipping, roads, railways", "optb": "shipping, roads, railways, air transport", "optc": "roads, railways, air transport, shipping", "optd": "railways, roads, shipping, air transport", "opte": "shipping, railways, roads, air transport.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On the recommendations of Indian Road Congress, the ruling gradient in plains, is", "opta": "1 in 15", "optb": "1 in 20", "optc": "1 in 30", "optd": "1 in 45", "opte": "1 in 100", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The head light of vehicles should be such that its lower beam illuminates objects at", "opta": "10 m", "optb": "20 m", "optc": "30 m", "optd": "40 m", "opte": "50 m", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The length of the side of warning sign boards of roads is", "opta": "30 cm", "optb": "40 cm", "optc": "45 cm", "optd": "50 cm", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A single lane carriage way whenever changes to two-lane carriage way, is affected through a taper of", "opta": "1 in 10", "optb": "1 in 15", "optc": "1 in 20", "optd": "1 in 15 to 1 in 20", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The wall constructed for the stability of an excavated portion of a road on the hill side, is known as", "opta": "retaining wall", "optb": "breast wall", "optc": "parapet wall", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum number of passenger cars that can pass a given point on a road during one hour under the most ideal road way and traffic conditions, is known as", "opta": "traffic density", "optb": "basic capacity of traffic lane", "optc": "possible capacity of traffic lane", "optd": "all the above.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}